Jonathan Krause Rare Newspaper and Magazine Collection 1648-1881 E302.1 .J76 E302.1 .J76
Lilly Library
Jonathan Krause Rare Newspaper and Magazine Collection
1648-1881
Lilly Library
E302.1 .J76
1000 items(ca.)
The Jonathan Krause Rare Newspaper and Magazine Collection consists of approximately 900 original issues of historical newspapers and magazines, with a focus on late 18th- and early 19th-century American publications.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Jonathan Krause is a retired Southern California teacher, with a strong and longstanding interest in American history. He assembled this collection of historical newspapers over approximately ten years. He was diligent in finding materials in the field, particularly newspaper publications of writings by the so-called Founding Fathers of the United States.
Scope and Contents Note
The Jonathan Krause Rare Newspaper and Magazine Collection consists of approximately 900 original issues of historical newspapers and magazines, with a focus on late 18th- and early 19th-century American publications. Mr. Krause's goal in building the collection was to focus on issues that included the texts of writings by important historical figures. This is an often overlooked area of historical research, in that many scholars look primarily at early monographic publications, rather than periodicals. Printed books and pamphlets typically cost a great deal more than periodicals, and so their readership was necessarily more limited in many respects. The essays, letters, speeches, and excerpts from larger works, which were often published in various periodicals, provide a glimpse into the ways these texts were disseminated to contemporary readers.
The newspapers and magazines are listed under categories and titles applied by Mr. Krause, with his notes on selected items included. Titles established by Mr. Krause are listed in all capitals.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 2016
Adams, John, 1735-1826; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790; Hamilton, Alexander, 1757-1804; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865; Madison, James, 1751-1836; Napoleon I, Emperor of the French, 1769-1821; Paine, Thomas, 1737-1809; Toussaint Louverture, 1743-1803; Washington, George, 1732-1799
- Colonial American and Early Republic Individuals
  - John Adams
    - VICE-PRESIDENTIAL INAUGURAL ADDRESS, American Museum Magazine, June 1789; Size: Small (Item 3)
      General
      First in American history.
      Includes Benjamin Franklin 122 and Bill of Rights 642
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Independent Chronicle, November 30, 1797 (Item 12)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Farmer's Weekly Museum, December 24, 1798 (Item 17)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Farmer's Museum, December 16, 1799 (Item 23)
      Includes Toussaint Louverture 414
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Providence Journal, December 3, 1800 (Item 26)
    - EXCERPTS FROM A DEFENSE OF THE CONSTITUTIONS OF GOVERNMENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, Massachusetts Gazette, July 17, 20, 24, August 24, 28, October 19, 1787 (Item 1)
      Includes Shays' Rebellion 674 (July 17, 24, October 19); Constitution 636 (August 24, 28); Thomas Jefferson 239 (August 28); and John Hancock 228 (October 19)
    - DISCOURSE ON DAVILA IV (actually ll), Gazette of the United States, May 15, 1790 (Item 6)
      Adams perspective on Renaissance politics and inferentially on his own time, prompting Jefferson to label him as a monarchist and causing a rupture between them.
      Includes Benjamin Franklin 128
    - DISCOURSE ON DAVILA VI (actually IV), Gazette of the United States, May 22, 1790 (Item 7)
      2 copies
    - DISCOURSE ON DAVILA XIV, Gazette of the United States, May 1, 1790 (Item 5)
      Includes Edmond Burke 52 and George Washington 576
    - DISCOURSE ON DAVILA XXIII, Gazette of the United States, November 20, 1790 (Item 8)
    - DISCOURSE ON DAVILA XXXI, Gazette of the United States, April 20, 1791 (Item 9)
      Includes James Madison 445
    - DISCOURSE ON DAVILA XXXII, Gazette of the United States, April 27, 1791 (Item 10)
      Last, most controversial of these essays and omitted from definitive first edition book of 1805 by Adams. Sealed the opinion of the Jeffersonians and history that Adams was a monocrat and an elitist. Found nowhere else but in this newspaper.
    - LETTER TO INHABITANTS OF PROVIDENCE, Columbian Centinel, May 9, 1798 (Item 15)
    - LETTER TO JAY ADVOCATING NEW CONSTITUTION, Pennsylvania Packet, April 18, 1788 (Item 2)
    - LETTERS NUMBERS XIII, XIV TO HENDRIK CALKOEN ON AMERICA, Gazette of the United States, November 25, 28, 1789 (Item 4)
      Originally written in 1780.
      See: Benjamin Franklin 125 (November 25) and Benjamin Franklin 126 (November 28)
    - LARGE EXTRACT OF LETTER TO JEFFERSON, Columbian Centinel, December 12, 1792 (Item 11)
      See: Thomas Paine 497 and Joseph Priestly 539
    - MESSAGE TO CONGRESS, Massachusetts Spy, April 4, 1798 (Item 13)
      2 copies (also Thomas Paine 504)
    - PROCLAMATIONS RECOMMENDING A NATIONAL DAY OF HUMILIATION, FASTING, AND PRAYER, Federal Gazette, April 4, 1798 (Item 14)
      Documents of such devoutness and religiosity unlike anything by Washington and Lincoln, or any other American president or politician.
    - SEDITION ACT, Massachusetts Spy, August 15, 1798 (Item 16)
    - "SPURIOUS ENVOYS" COLUMN ABOUT XYZ AFFAIR AND QUASI-WAR BETWEEN FRANCE AND UNITED STATES, Porcupine's Gazette, January 22, 1799 (Item 961)
    - XYZ AFFAIR (Pickering letter to Gerry), Massachusetts Spy, February 6, 1799 (Item 18)
    - XYZ AFFAIR, Columbian Centinel, February 6, 1799 (Item 19)
    - PROCLAMATIONS RECOMMENDING A NATIONAL DAY OF HUMILIATION, FASTING, AND PRAYER, Columbian Centinel, March 20, 1799 (Item 20)
    - PROCLAMATION ON FRIES REBELLION, Massachusetts Spy, March 27, 1799 (Item 21)
    - PROCLAMATION ON TRADE WITH ST. DOMINGO, J. Russell's Gazette, Connecticut Courant, July 8, 1799 (Item 22)
      First recognition of a black government in history, continuing the trade agreement—the so-called Toussaint clause—with St. Domingo (Haiti), led by ex-slave Toussaint Louverture, in revolt against France.
    - PROCLAMATION ON REMISSION OF TRADE PROHIBITION WITH HISPANIOLA, Connecticut Courant, May 26, 1800 (Item 25)
    - FUNERAL OF WASHINGTON AND ADAMS' PROCLAMATION, Connecticut Courant, January 13, 1800 (Item 24)
      See: George Washington 608
    - REPORT ON CORRESPONDENCE FROM TALLEYRAND (FRENCH MINISTER OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS) DURING QUASI-WAR, REPORT ON INTERCEPTING EGYPTIAN CORRESPONDENCE DURING NAPOLEON'S CAMPAIGN IN EGYPT AND SYRIA, The Sun, January 25, 1800 (Item 962)
    - CORRESPONDENCE OF PRESIDENT ADAMS, Boston Patriot, June 28, July 8, 26, August 19, 30, November 8, 1809, July 21, October 13, 1810 (Item 27)
      8 documents
    - LETTER ON PEACE AND WAR, New York Evening Post, July 10, 1816 (Item 28)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 308
    - LETTER ON PEACE AND WAR, Niles Weekly Register, July 13, 1816; Size: Small (Item 29)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 309
    - VERY RARE LETTER TO MANUEL NOAH ON JEWS AND RELIGIOUS FREEDOM, Niles' Weekly Register, February 20, 1819; Size: Small (Item 30)
      Supplement to Volume 15 (page 10).
      Includes Thomas Jefferson 312, James Madison 466, and Mordecai Manuel Noah 841
  - John Quincy Adams
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE REFERRING TO DEATH OF ADAMS AND JEFFERSON, Middlesex Gazette, December 13, 1826 (Item 44)
    - PUBLICOLA I, Gazette of the United States, June 18, 1791 (Item 33)
      One of the most significant series of political essays in American history, especially from the conservative viewpoint.
    - PUBLICOLA II, Columbian Centinel, June 11, 1791 (Item 31)
    - PUBLICOLA III, Columbian Centinel, June 15, 1791 (Item 32)
    - PUBLICOLA IV, Columbian Centinel, June 18, 1791 (Item 34)
    - PUBLICOLA V, Columbian Centinel, June 22, 1791 (Item 35)
    - PUBLICOLA VI, Columbian Centinel, June 29, 1791 (Item 36)
      Includes Edmund Burke 54
    - PUBLICOLA VII, Gazette of the United States, July 13, 1791 (Item 38)
    - PUBLICOLA VIII, Columbian Centinel, July 9, 1791 (Item 37)
    - PUBLICOLA IX, Columbian Centinel, July 13, 1791 (Item 39)
    - PUBLICOLA X, Columbian Centinel, July 20, 1791 (Item 40)
      Includes Edmund Burke 55
    - PUBLICOLA XI, Columbian Centinel, July 27, 1791 (Item 41)
      Includes Edmond Burke 55
    - PUBLICOLA XI, Gazette of United States, August 6, 1791 (Item 42)
    - FOURTH OF JULY SPEECH ON AMERICAN HISTORY, Niles' Weekly Register, July 21, 1821; Size: Small (Item 43)
    - CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN JOHN QUINCY ADAMS, ESQUIRE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES, AND SEVERAL CITIZENS OF MASSACHUSSETTS CONCERNING THE CHARGE OF A DESIGN TO DISSOLVE THE UNION ALLEGED TO HAVE EXISTED IN THAT STATE, 1829; Size: Small (Item 990)
      Pamphlet.
  - Fisher Ames
    - AN ORATION ON THE SUBLIME VIRTUES OF GENERAL GEORGE WASHINGTON, The Columbian Phoenix or Boston Review, March 1800; Size: Small (Item 45)
  - Benedict Arnold
    - PROCLAMATION TO THE OFFICERS AND SOLDIERS OF THE CONTINENTAL ARMY AND LETTER CONCERNING ANDRE AFFAIR, ANDRE LETTER AND EXTENSIVE COVERAGE OF ARNOLD AND ANDRE SCANDAL, Edinburgh Evening Courant, December 6, 1780; Size: Small (Item 46)
      A traitor tries to seduce and inveigle the American troops to desert to the British side.
      See: Alexander Hamilton 129 and George Washington 546
  - Joel Barlow
    - ADDRESS TO NATIONAL ASSEMBLY OF FRANCE, Columbian Centinel, October 6, 1790 (Item 47)
      Expressing an almost religious love of and belief in France and its revolution.
  - Edmund Burke
    - SPEECH ON MOVING HIS RESOLUTIONS FOR CONCILIATION WITH THE COLONIES, Pennsylvania Evening Post, September 21, 1775; Size: Small (Item 48)
    - LETTER ON THE AFFAIRS OF AMERICA, London Chronicle, May 22, 1777; Size: Small (Item 49)
    - THOUGHTS ON THE LETTER OF EDMUND BURKE TO THE SHERIFFS OF BRISTOL ON THE AFFAIRS OF AMERICA BY EARL OF ABINGDON, London Chronicle, September 6, 1777; Size: Small (Item 50)
    - SPEECH OPPOSING FRENCH REVOLUTION, London Chronicle, February 11, 1790; Size: Small (Item 51)
      One of the most famous and historic speeches of the eighteenth century.
    - SPEECH OPPOSING FRENCH REVOLUTION, Gazette of the United States, May 1, 1790 (Item 52)
    - DEBATE WITH CHARLES FOX ON THE FRENCH REVOLUTION, London Chronicle, May 7, 1791; Size: Small (Item 53)
    - EXTRACT OF LETTER ON FRENCH REVOLUTION, Columbian Centinel, June 29, 1791 (Item 54)
      See: John Quincy Adams 36
    - DEBATE WITH CHARLES FOX ON THE FRENCH REVOLUTION, Columbian Centinel, July 20, 27, 1791 (Item 55)
      See: John Quincy Adams 40 (July 20) and John Quincy Adams 41 (July 27)
  - Aaron Burr
    - LETTER OF DENIAL IN 1800 ELECTION CONSPIRACY, New York Herald, October 2, 1802 (Item 56)
      Includes Anti-Jefferson 337, Toussaint Louverture 435, and Napoleon Bonaparte 898. 2 copies (also Anti-Jefferson 336)
    - BURR/HAMILTON CORRESPONDENCE, The Repertory, July 20, 1804 (Item 58)
      See: Alexander Hamilton 227
    - TRIAL AND CONSPIRACY, The Balance, December 2, 9, 30, 1806, February 10, October 6, 1807; Size: Small (Item 59)
      Includes Thomas Jefferson 291
    - TRIAL AND CONSPIRACY, National Aegis, February 4, 1807 (Item 60)
      Includes Thomas Jefferson 292
    - TRIAL AND CONSPIRACY (including Wilkinson and Jefferson), New York Herald, June 10, 1807 (Item 61)
    - TRIAL AND CONSPIRACY, American Citizen, June 23, October 29, 1807 (Item 62)
      Includes Thomas Paine 517
    - TRIAL AND CONSPIRACY, American Mercury, September 24, 1807 (Item 63)
  - Tench Coxe
    - THE FEDERALIST NO. III -- ESSAY AGAINST ADAMS AND BY INFERENCE FOR JEFFERSON IN 1796 ELECTION, WRITTEN IN RESPONSE TO THE PHOCION ESSAYS AUTHORED BY HAMILTON/WILLIAM LOUGHTON SMITH AGAINST JEFFERSON (See Hamilton Item 201), Gazette of the United States, November 14, 1796 (Item 1077)
      Coxe was a writer on the Constitution and economic issues and a government official, who had once supplied the statistical data for Hamilton's important Report on Manufactures (1791), and was appointed Assistant Secretary of the Treasury by Hamilton. He had been a Federalist but decided to join Jefferson's Democratic Republicans. In The Federalist essays, he derided Adams as a closet monocrat and aristocratic sympathizer, as Jefferson had done years earlier in a private letter that had been made public, precipitating a feud that lasted more than twenty years. After Adam's victory, Jefferson would become Vice-President, but the two would barely speak during Adams' presidency -- Jefferson being shut out of all important decisions, mainly by the cabinet, who were mostly holdovers from Washington's administration, and Hamilton's personal squad of spies, although he was no longer in government.
  - Stephen Decatur
    - LETTERS ON CHESAPEAKE - NORFOLK AFFAIR, New York Herald, November 28, 1807 (Item 64)
      See: Thomas Paine 518
  - John Dickinson
    - LETTERS FROM A FARMER IN PENNSYLVANIA I, Boston Chronicle, December 21, 1767; Size: Small (Item 65)
      The most famous and significant political essays written before the American Revolution, No. 1 being the rarest and most historical of the series.
    - LETTERS FROM A FARMER IN PENNSYLVANIA II, Boston Chronicle, December 21, 1767; Size: Small (Item 66)
    - LETTERS FROM A FARMER IN PENNSYLVANIA III AND IV, Boston Chronicle, January 4, 1768; Size: Small (Item 67)
    - LETTERS FROM A FARMER IN PENNSYLVANIA VIII, Boston Chronicle, February 8, 1768; Size: Small (Item 68)
    - LETTERS FROM A FARMER IN PENNSYLVANIA XI AND XII, Boston Chronicle, March 7, 1768; Size: Small (Item 69)
    - DECLARATION OF CAUSES AND NECESSITY OF TAKING UP ARMS, Gentleman's Magazine, August 1775; Size: Small (Item 70)
      With Jefferson. Last milestone on road to Declaration of Independence
      See: Thomas Jefferson 238
    - VINDICATION OF CAREER DURING AMERICAN REVOLUTION, Pennsylvania Journal, January 1, 8, 15, 22, 1783 (Item 71)
    - FABIUS VI, Pennsylvania Mercury, April 24, 1788; Size: Small (Item 72)
      Besides the Federalist Papers, the most important essays supporting ratification of the Constitution, especially favored by Washington.
    - FABIUS IX, Pennsylvania Mercury, May 1, 1788; Size: Small (Item 73)
  - Benjamin Franklin
    - SPEECH OF MISS POLLY BAKER, Gentleman's Magazine, April 1747; Size: Small (Item 74)
      First work of Franklin published in England.
    - LETTER TO PETER COLLINSON ON ELECTRICAL EXPERIMENTS, Gentleman's Magazine, May 1750; Size: Small (Item 75)
    - ALBANY PLAN, Gentleman's Magazine, October 1754; Size: Small (Item 76)
    - OBSERVATIONS CONCERNING THE INCREASE OF MANKIND, Gentleman's Magazine, November 1755; Size: Small (Item 77)
    - PENNSYLVANIA MILITIA BILL AND A DIALOGUE BETWEEN X,Y, AND Z CONCERNING THE PRESENT STATE OF AFFAIRS IN PENNSYLVANIA, Gentleman's Magazine, February, March, 1756; Size: Small (Item 78)
      Perhaps the first political essay of Franklin's published in England.
    - QUERIES ADDRESSED TO A FRIEND OF LORD BALTIMORE, London Chronicle, September 19, 1758; Size: Small (Item 79)
      First political essay Franklin published in England.
    - A DEFENSE OF THE PROVINCIALS, London Chronicle, May 12, 1759; Size: Small (Item 80)
    - AN ACCOUNT OF THE EFFECTS OF ELECTRICITY IN PARALYTIC CASES, London Chronicle, July 3, 1759; Size: Small (Item 81)
    - OF THE MEANS OF DISPOSING THE ENEMIES TO PEACE, London Chronicle, August 13, 1761; Size: Small (Item 82)
    - A NARRATIVE OF THE LATE MASSACRES, Gentleman's Magazine, April 1764; Size: Small (Item 83)
    - ON CHASTISING THE COLONIES, London Chronicle, February 13, 1766; Size: Small (Item 84)
    - EXTRACT FROM A PAMPHLET AND A REPLY TO COFFEE-HOUSE ORATORS, London Chronicle, April 9, 1767; Size: Small (Item 85)
    - EXAMINATION OF DR. FRANKLIN, Gentleman's Magazine, July, 1767, September, 1774; Size: Small (Item 86)
    - EXAMINATION OF DR. FRANKLIN, London Chronicle, July 9, 1767; Size: Small (Item 87)
    - AMERICAN LONGEVITY, London Chronicle, December 15, 1767; Size: Small (Item 88)
    - CAUSES OF AMERICAN DISCONTENTS BEFORE 1768 AND SUBJECT OF SUBJECTS, Gentleman's Magazine, January 1768; Size: Small (Item 89)
    - ESSAY ON THE POOR, Gentleman's Magazine, April 1768; Size: Small (Item 90)
    - ON ABSENTEE GOVERNORS, London Chronicle, August 27, 1768; Size: Small (Item 91)
    - HILLSBOROUGH AND AMHERST, London Chronicle, August 30, 1768; Size: Small (Item 92)
    - OPEN LETTER TO DENNYS DE BERDT, Gentleman's Magazine, September 1768; Size: Small (Item 93)
    - SINECURES FOR FRIENDS AND FAVORITES, London Chronicle, September 29, 1768; Size: Small (Item 94)
    - ADVANTAGES OF AMERICAN MANUFACTURES, London Chronicle, January 27, 1770; Size: Small (Item 95)
    - THE COLONIST'S ADVOCATE, NUMBER X, London Chronicle, February 22, 1770; Size: Small (Item 96)
    - EXPOSTULATION, London Chronicle, November 6, 1770; Size: Small (Item 97)
    - RULES BY WHICH A GREAT EMPIRE MAY BE REDUCED TO A SMALL ONE, Gentleman's Magazine, September 1773; Size: Small (Item 98)
      Includes Phyllis Wheatley 610
    - AN EDICT BY THE KING OF PRUSSIA, Gentleman's Magazine, October 1773; Size: Small (Item 99)
    - ARTICLES OF CONFEDERATION, Lloyd's Evening Post, December 8, 1775; Size: Small (Item 100)
      One of the founding documents of America and the basis for the Articles of Confederation adopted by Congress under which we operated until the Constitution.
    - LETTER TO LORD HOWE ABOUT THE WAR, Gentleman's Magazine, April 1777; Size: Small (Item 101)
    - LETTER TO LORD NORTH ON PRISONERS OF WAR, Connecticut Courant, May 26, 1778 (Item 102)
      With Silas Deane and Arthur Lee.
      Includes Revolutionary War 627
    - MEMORIAL TO COURT OF VERSAILLES, Edinburgh Advertiser, September 10, 1779; Size: Small (Item 103)
    - LETTER TO LAFAYETTE, London Chronicle, September 14, 1779; Size: Small (Item 104)
    - POLITICAL FRAGMENTS, Edinburgh Evening Courant, February 7, 1780; Size: Small (Item 105)
    - LETTER TO UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA, Pennsylvania Packet, September 17, 1785 (Item 106)
    - LETTER TO CONSTITUTIONAL SOCIETY, Pennsylvania Packet, September 19, 1785 (Item 107)
    - LETTERS TO MILITIA AND JUSTICES OF PHILADELPHIA, Pennsylvania Packet, September 20, 1785 (Item 108)
    - LETTER TO AMERICAN PHILOSOPHICAL SOCIETY, Pennsylvania Packet, October 1, 1785 (Item 109)
    - LETTER TO THE PENNSYLVANIA GENERAL ASSEMBLY ON STATE MATTERS, Pennsylvania Packet, November 17, 1785 (Item 110)
    - TRUE DESCRIPTION OF THE INTEREST AND POLICY OF THE CONTINENT OF AMERICA, London Chronicle, July 20, 1786; Size: Small (Item 111)
      Includes extract of Washington letter.
    - LETTER TO PENNSYLVANIA GENERAL ASSEMBLY ON LAND DISPUTES, Pennsylvania Packet, February 24, 1787 (Item 112)
    - PROCLAMATION ON REWARD FOR SHAYS' REBELLION REBELS, Pennsylvania Packet, March 26, 1787 (Item 113)
    - LETTER TO BOWDOIN ON SHAYS' REBELLION, Pennsylvania Packet, April 3, 1787 (Item 114)
    - METEOROLOGICAL IMAGINATIONS AND CONJECTURE, American Museum Magazine, June 1787; Size: Small (Item 115)
      See: Alexander Hamilton 132
    - SPEECH TO THE CONSTITUTIONAL CONVENTION, American Museum Magazine, December 1787; Size: Small (Item 116)
      One of the most famous in American history.
      See: Alexander Hamilton 134
    - LETTER TO PENNSYLVANIA GENERAL ASSEMBLY ON CONSTITUTION, PURCHASE OF LAND, ORPHANS, PENAL REFORM, ETC., Pennsylvania Packet, February 25, 1788 (Item 117)
    - ON THE CONSTITUTION, Gentleman's Magazine, February 1789; Size: Small (Item 118)
    - ALBANY PLAN, American Museum Magazine, April 1789; Size: Small (Item 119)
      First mention of a possible union of the American colonies.
      Includes George Washington 562, George Washington 563, and Bill of Rights 642
    - REMARKS ON THE NORTH AMERICAN INDIANS (REMARKS CONCERNING THE SAVAGES OF NORTH AMERICA), American Museum Magazine, April 1789; Size: Small (Item 120)
    - IDEA OF AN ENGLISH SCHOOL, American Museum Magazine, May 1789; Size: Small (Item 121)
      Includes James Madison 444, George Washington 565, and George Washington 566
    - PHYSICAL AND METEOROLOGICAL OBSERVATIONS, American Museum Magazine, June 1789 (Item 122)
      See: John Adams 3
    - ADDRESS FROM THE PENNSYLVANIA SOCIETY FOR PROMOTING THE ABOLITION OF SLAVERY, American Museum Magazine, November 1789; Size: Small (Item 123)
      Includes Benjamin Franklin 124 and George Washington 572
    - PLAN FOR IMPROVING THE CONDITION OF FREE BLACKS, American Museum Magazine, November 1789; Size: Small (Item 124)
      See: Benjamin Franklin 123
    - ADDRESS FROM THE PENNSYLVANIA SOCIETY FOR PROMOTING THE ABOLITION OF SLAVERY, Gazette of the United States, November 25, 1789 (Item 125)
      Includes John Adams 4, George Washington 574, and French Revolution 935
    - PLAN FOR IMPROVING THE CONDITION OF FREE BLACKS, Gazette of the United States, November 28, 1789 (Item 126)
      Includes John Adams 4 and Benjamin Franklin 127
    - LETTER TO SAMUEL MATHERS, Gazette of the United States, November 28, 1789 (Item 127)
      See: Benjamin Franklin 126
    - FRANKLIN WILL, Gazette of the United States, May 15, 1790 (Item 128)
      See: John Adams 6
  - Alexander Hamilton
    - RARE REVOLUTIONARY WAR LETTER TO ISAAC SEARS ON GOVERNMENT, WAR, TAXES, AN ARMY, FOREIGN LOANS, ETC., Edinburgh Evening Courant, December 6, 1780; Size: Small (Item 129)
      Includes Benedict Arnold 46 and George Washington 546
    - LETTER TO LAFAYETTE ON BATTLE OF YORKTOWN, London Chronicle, December 22, 1781; Size: Small (Item 130)
      See: George Washington 548
    - SPEECH ON IMPOST (second edition), American Museum Magazine, June 1787; Size: Small (Item 132)
      Includes Benjamin Franklin 115
    - FEDERALIST NO. 1, American Museum Magazine, November 1787; Size: Small (Item 133)
      First and only appearance of a Federalist Paper in an American magazine, including Numbers 2-6.
      Includes John Jay 230 and Thomas Jefferson 240
    - FEDERALIST NO. 6, American Museum Magazine, December 1787; Size: Small (Item 134)
      Includes Benjamin Franklin 116 and John Jay 231, John Jay 232, John Jay 233
    - AT NEW YORK RATIFYING CONVENTION, Connecticut Courant, July 28, 1788 (Item 135)
    - LETTER TO THE SUPERVISORS OF THE CITY OF ALBANY ON THE CONSTITUTION, NATIONAL GOVERNMENT AND THE UNION, New York Daily Advertiser, February 20, 1789 (Item 137)
    - POLITICAL ANNOUNCEMENT TO THE CITIZENS OF NEW YORK, New York Daily Advertiser, February 27, 1789 (Item 138)
    - LETTER ON THE ELECTORS OF THE CITY AND COUNTY OF NEW YORK ON THE CONSTITUTION, MENTION OF AMENDMENTS, AND THE BEGINNING OF THE NEW CONSTITUTIONAL GOVERNMENT, New York Daily Advertiser, March 3, 1789 (Item 139)
    - H.G. LETTER I, New York Daily Advertiser, March 10, 1789 (Item 140)
      Attacking in the letters the character of Governor Clinton as the leader of the Anti-Federalist (anti-Constitutional) forces. Hamilton reviews the constitutional issues before and during ratification process to show unfitness of Clinton to be re-elected governor of New York.
    - H.G. LETTER II, New York Daily Advertiser, March 11, 1789 (Item 141)
    - H.G. LETTER III, New York Daily Advertiser, March 12, 1789 (Item 142)
    - H.G. LETTER IV, New York Daily Advertiser, March 14, 1789 (Item 143)
    - H.G. LETTER V, New York Daily Advertiser, March 17, 1789 (Item 144)
    - H.G. LETTER VI, New York Daily Advertiser, March 18, 1789 (Item 145)
    - H.G. LETTER VII, New York Daily Advertiser, March 19, 1789 (Item 146)
    - H.G. LETTER VIII, New York Daily Advertiser, March 20, 1789 (Item 147)